Guide to the Maurice Crain Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Maurice Crain Papers
1946-1970.
Crain, Maurice, 1901-1970.
16 linear ft (ca. 3,200 items in 38 boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
MS#0301
4078662
This collection contains the correspondence, business papers and finanial records, 1946-1970, of literary agent, Maurice Crain, 1901-1970.
Biographical Note
New York literary agent. Maurice Crain was the husband of Annie Laurie Williams.
Scope and Content
The papers and financial records of Crain. Among the novelists and short story writers included in the collection are Frank Gilbreth, Ernestine Gilbreth Carey, Ruth Goode, Fred Gipson, and John Green.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in two series:
Series I: Correspondence
Series II: Business Papers
Subjects
Williams, Annie Laurie.; Gilbreth, Frank B. (Frank Bunker), 1911-2001.; Carey, Ernestine Gilbreth.; Goode, Ruth.; Gipson, Fred, 1908-1973.; Green, John.; American literature--20th century.; Authors, American--20th century.; Literature publishing--New York (State)--New York.; Financial records.; Literary agents.
Acquisition
1970 M-70 Williams, Annie Laurie Gift
Gift of Annie Laurie Williams, 1970 & 1974.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
- Series I: Correspondence
  - A-Be (Box 1)
  - Bo-By (Box 2)
  - C-D (Box 3)
  - E (Box 4)
  - Loula G. Erdman (Box 5-6)
  - F-Goode (Box 7)
  - Goode (cont.)-Gr (Box 8)
  - Frank & Ernestine Gilbreth (Box 9-10)
  - Fred Gipson (Box 11)
  - John Green (Box 12-13)
  - H (Box 14)
  - I-K (Box 15)
  - L-Me (Box 16)
  - Michael Leahy (Box 17)
  - Mi-O (Box 18)
  - P-Ra (Box 19)
  - Re-Ru (Box 20)
  - S-Wi (Box 21)
  - Wh-Z (Box 22)
  - 1963-1968
    - A-E (Box 23)
    - F-L (Box 24)
    - M-R (Box 25)
    - S-Z (Box 26)
  - 1969-1970
    - A-J (Box 27)
    - K-Z (Box 28)
- World War II: Letters, etc. (Box 29)
- Series II: Business Papers
  - Submission Book (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 31)
  - Cancelled Checks
    - 1954-1958 (Box 32)
    - 1959-1961 (Box 33)
    - 1962, 1964-1965 (Box 34)
  - Deposit Slips: 1958-1960 Check Stubs: 1959-1960 (Box 35)
  - Deposit Slips: 1961-62, 1964-67; Cancelled Checks: 1967 Bank Books: 1967 (Box 36)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 37)
  - Manuscripts of Maurice Crain (Gift of Annie Laurie Williams, 1974) (Box 38)